Robert B. Brigham Hospital. Records, 1889–1984 (Bulk 1915–1980): Finding Aid.
Records, 1889–1984 (Bulk 1915–1980).
- X. Photographs, circa 1950s–circa 1980., (1 record carton, 2 flat document boxes.)
  - (Box 5: Folders 1–44.)
    - Research and Labs, circa 1960–circa 1970., 5.
    - Laboratory Photographs, 1965–1971., 6.
    - Occupational Therapy, 1965–1976., 7.
    - RBBH Nursing, 1923–1977., 8.
    - Robert Breck Brigham, Nursing, 1963–1977., 9.
    - Physical Therapy, circa 1970., 10.
    - Clinical Laboratories, circa 1960–circa 1970., 11.
    - Physical Therapy, circa 1920–1974., 12.
    - RBBH Administrative Staff, circa 1960–circa 1970., 13.
    - Robert and Elizabeth Brigham, undated., 14.
    - Joints, splints, and casts, undated., 15.
    - RBBH Employees, 1968–1979., 16.
    - Physical and Occupational Therapy, circa 1960–circa 1970., 17.
    - Physical and Occupational Therapy, circa 1940–circa 1970., 18.
    - RBBH Staff and Associates, circa 1945–circa 1975., 19.
    - RBBH Medical Staff, circa 1960–1976., 20.
    - RBBH Staff, 1923–circa 1970., 21.
    - RBBH Special Events, 1953–1978., 22.
    - RBBH Teaching, undated., 23.
    - VIPs Visiting RBBH Patients, 1970., 24.
    - Patients, 1923–1939., 25.
    - RBBH Patients, 1952–1964., 26.
    - RBBH Patients, circa 1950–circa 1980., 27.
    - RBBH Facilities, circa 1920–circa 1960., 28.
    - Miscellaneous photographs, circa 1974., 29.
    - RBBH Negatives, 1929–circa 1970., 30.; Most of the negatives in this folder are copy negatives of prints located in the other image folders in this collection.
    - Artwork, General, 1971–1977., 31.
    - Patient X-mas Party, 1963., 32.
    - Patient’s X-mas Party, 1974., 33.
    - Christmas Parties, circa 1960–1970., 34.
    - Patient X-mas Party, 1971., 35.
    - X-mas Parties, 1962, 1964, 1965, 1970., 36.
    - X-mas Party, 1969., 37.
    - RBBH Service Awards, 1974., 38.
    - RBBH Softball, 1975., 39.
    - Volunteers, circa 1970., 40.
    - RBBH Employees, 1965–1975., 41.
    - RBBH School for Child Patients, circa 1930., 42.
    - RBBH Party, circa 1980., 43.
    - RBBH Slides, Building Exterior, Patients, circa 1965., 44.
  - (Box 6:)
    - Occupational and Physical Therapy, circa 1920–circa 1970., 2 (8" x 10" matted), 4 (10" x 12"), and 2 (11" x 14") photographs of unidentified patients during physical therapy.
  - (Box 7:)
    - Pond Avenue view of the Free Hospital for Women, undated., 1 (11" x 14") photograph.
    - View from Mission Hill, undated., 1 (9" x 14") photograph.
    - Facade of the Robert B. Brigham Hospital, undated., 1 matted (11" x 14") illustration.
    - Unidentified man leaning against a car, circa 1930., 1 (11" x 14") photograph.
- XI. Memorabilia, 1959–1961., (1 folder, 2 items.)
  - (Box 4: Folder 22.)
    - RBBH Scrapbook, 1959–1961., 22.; Original scrapbook contained acidic newspaper clippings and pages in an advanced state of decay. Photocopies were made of each page onto buffered, acid-free paper and the originals were discarded.
  - (Box 4: Items 28–29.)
    - Hanging Plaque for John Henry Gibbs, 1916., 28.
    - Box of Service Award Pins, 1978., 29.; 21 pins, including 7 five-year, 1 ten-year, 6 fifteen-year, 3 twenty-year, 2 thirty-year, and 2 thirty-five-year. Each pin is in its original, individual plastic box.
- XII. Resource and Reference Materials, 1889–1984., (5 folders, 6 volumes.)
  Contains article saved for reference and includes six bound collections of the printed articles written (some before the creation of the Robert B. Brigham Hospital) by staff, published in various medical journals from 1889–1968. The condition of these documents is fragile.
  - (Box 4: Folders 23–27.)
    - The Arthritis Foundation, 1971–1977., 23.
    - The Arthritis Foundation, 1969–1977., 24.
    - Research articles written or collected by RBBH staff, 1964–1980., 25.
    - Research articles written or collected by RBBH staff, 1903, 1922, 1943, 1976–1984., 26.; Includes two letters from 1984 regarding Dr. Matthew Liang’s plans for a symposium on juvenile arthritis.
    - Research articles written or collected by RBBH staff, 1910–1946., 27.
  - (Box 8: Items 1–6.)
    - Staff Publications Volume I, 1889–1922., 1.
    - Staff Publications Volume II, 1923–1935., 2.
    - Staff Publications Volume III, 1936–1945., 3.
    - Staff Publications Volume IV, 1946–1959., 4.
    - Staff Publications Volume V, 1959–1965., 5.
    - Staff Publications Volume VI, 1966–1968., 6.